<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dl on Better Tomorrow with Computer Science</title>
    <link>/tags/dl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dl on Better Tomorrow with Computer Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 16:10:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/dl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using HuggingFace Transformers</title>
      <link>/2023-04-19/using-huggingface-transformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 16:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023-04-19/using-huggingface-transformers/</guid>
      <description>HF Transformers # HuggingFace (🤗) Transformers is a library that enables to easily download the state-of-the-art pretrained models. It is also possible to create and train a model from scratch, after modifying the structure of existing models. Although the library starts from transformer based language models, it became a general community hub and includes other models such as convolution based Resnet.
It can easily be installed via pip 1:
pip install transformers  Most code is borrowed from HuggingFace transformers example codes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Parallelization of Attention</title>
      <link>/2022-08-03/analyzing-parallelization-of-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022-08-03/analyzing-parallelization-of-attention/</guid>
      <description>We exploit the inherent parallelism in the multi-head attention operation to partition the self-attention block (shown in Figure 5b). The key (K), Query (Q), and value (V) matrices can be partitioned in a column-parallel fashion. The output linear layer can then directly operate on the partitioned output of the attention operation (weight matrix partitioned across rows).
Deepak Narayanan et al, Efficient large-scale language model training on GPU clusters using megatron-LM, SC&#39;21</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Transformer Model</title>
      <link>/2022-07-30/analysis-of-transformer-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 23:48:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022-07-30/analysis-of-transformer-model/</guid>
      <description>This post analyzes transformer models, specifically memory and computation overhead.
Many transformer based models just explain themselves as a model with X-B parameters; I wanted to break it down and look into the model structure how they are stored and used in actual computing hardware.
 Many illustrations and analysis are based on the following papers 1.
 Transformer-based Model # Since Google announed attention and transformer models in 2017 2, MLP and image classification models are rapidly adopting transformer layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallelism in Distributed Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/2022-06-11/parallelism-in-distributed-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 19:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022-06-11/parallelism-in-distributed-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Distributed deep learning refers to use a distributed system that includes several workers to perform inference or training deep learning. Since mid 2010, people have been thinking about accelerating deep learning with scale-out, and distributd deep learning has been introduced. Parameter server is one of the well-known architecture for distributed deep learning.
Recent days, many parallelization mechanisms, the way of distributing computation to multiple workers, have been introduced. First one was to split batches into several microbatches and distributed it, namely data parallelism, which the parameter server architecture is for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
