<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Better Tomorrow with Computer Science</title>
    <link>/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Better Tomorrow with Computer Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 11:13:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Torch FX Transformation and Pipeline Parallelism</title>
      <link>/2023-04-22/torch-fx-transformation-and-pipeline-parallelism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 11:13:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023-04-22/torch-fx-transformation-and-pipeline-parallelism/</guid>
      <description>Torch fx # torch.fx is a PyTorch module that captures a model and applies transformation for optimization 1. In recent days, the importance of model optimization is getting more important. torch.fx enables transparent transformation without touching to the original model implementation, allowing fine-grained model optimization.
Since PyTorch 2.0, it seems TorchDynamo replaces legacy fx.tracer for tracing the model. This post focuses on existing torch.fx module, and I will post another one regarding TorchDynamo if I have a chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using HuggingFace Transformers</title>
      <link>/2023-04-19/using-huggingface-transformers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 16:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023-04-19/using-huggingface-transformers/</guid>
      <description>HF Transformers # HuggingFace (🤗) Transformers is a library that enables to easily download the state-of-the-art pretrained models. It is also possible to create and train a model from scratch, after modifying the structure of existing models. Although the library starts from transformer based language models, it became a general community hub and includes other models such as convolution based Resnet.
It can easily be installed via pip 1:
pip install transformers Most code is borrowed from HuggingFace transformers example codes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
