<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>spdk on Better Tomorrow with Computer Science</title>
    <link>/tags/spdk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in spdk on Better Tomorrow with Computer Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 09:02:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/spdk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Intel IOAT DMA</title>
      <link>/2021-04-26/using-intel-ioat-dma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 09:02:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021-04-26/using-intel-ioat-dma/</guid>
      <description>I/OAT (I/O Acceleration Technology) 1 # Intel I/OAT is a set of technologies for improving I/O performance. This post specifically illustrates how to use Intel QuickData Technology, which enables data copy by the chipset instead of the CPU, to move data more efficiently and provide fast throughput.
Using Linux DMA Engine # I/OAT (specifically QuickData Technology) is implemented as ioatdma kernel module in Linux, and integrated into the Linux DMA subsystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Ceph RBD as a QEMU Storage</title>
      <link>/2021-03-04/using-ceph-rbd-as-a-qemu-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 14:40:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021-03-04/using-ceph-rbd-as-a-qemu-storage/</guid>
      <description>This post explains how we can use a Ceph RBD as a QEMU storage. We can attach a Ceph RBD to a QEMU VM through either virtio-blk or vhost-user-blk QEMU device (vhost requires SPDK).
Assume that a Ceph cluster is ready following the manual.
Setting a Ceph client Configuration 1 # For a node to access a Ceph cluster, it requires some configuration:
Config file setup User authentication setup This step requires an access permission to a host; a host refers to a node that is already configured as a client or running a cluster daemon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
